<?hard-pagebreak?>
<section><title>Step 1: Download &amp; Install VirtualBox</title>

<para><emphasis>VirtualBox</emphasis><indexterm><primary>VirtualBox</primary></indexterm>
is a free and open-source virtualization solution. Download the version
for your <emphasis>current</emphasis> operating system &#8211; for example,
if you're on Windows, get the version for Windows, not Linux. The project's
main site is <ulink url="https://virtualbox.org"/>.</para>

<ulink url="https://virtualbox.org"><mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/VirtualBox-Download.png" format="PNG" align="center"></imagedata></imageobject></mediaobject></ulink>

</section>

<section><title>Step 2: Download &amp; Install Vagrant</title>

<para><emphasis>Vagrant</emphasis><indexterm><primary>Vagrant</primary></indexterm>
is a free and open-source project for managing virtual machines. As before,
download the version of Vagrant for your <emphasis>current</emphasis> operating
system. The site to go to is <ulink url="https://vagrantup.com"/>.</para>

<ulink url="https://vagrantup.com"><mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/Vagrant-Download.png" format="PNG" align="center"></imagedata></imageobject></mediaobject></ulink>

</section>

<section><title>Step 3: Download &amp; Install Linux in a VM</title>

<para>This is going to be super-easy with Vagrant.</para>

<para>Linux comes in many different flavors called
<emphasis>distributions</emphasis><indexterm><primary>distribution</primary></indexterm>.
A Linux distribution is a complete set of programs that together comprise
a full operating system.</para>

<para>You're now going to install a distribution called
<emphasis>Debian</emphasis>. To be more precise, you're going to install
a special version of Debian that integrates with VirtualBox very well. The
special version contains extensions that allow you to easily copy files to
and from a VirtualBox virtual machine.</para>

<para>At the time of this writing (June 2020), the latest version of Debian
is called <emphasis>buster</emphasis> and that's the version you're going
to install.</para>

<para>Vagrant knows how to configure a given virtual machine from a
configuration file called the <filename>Vagrantfile</filename>. Fortunately,
the Vagrantfile can be generated automatically, which is what we're going to
do :) You can keep the Vagrantfile anywhere you want on your hard drive.</para>

<para>To use Vagrant you need to enter the command line of your current
operating system. On Windows, open the File Explorer, navigate to the
directory where you want to keep the Vagrantfile (for example, the Documents
directory), press Shift&nbsp;+&nbsp;right-click on the directory and click
on "Open command window here" or "Open PowerShell window here". On MacOS,
open Finder, navigate to the directory where you want to keep the Vagrantfile
(for example, the Documents directory), right-click on the directory, go to
Services and click on "New Terminal at Folder".</para>

<para>Once in the command line, type in the following:</para>

<screen>vagrant init debian/contrib-buster64</screen>

<para>When the command finishes successfully, it should print a message that
it created the Vagrantfile in your current directory.</para>

<note><title>Want to try another distribution?</title><para>This book
is written in a way that allows you to use any major Linux distribution
to practice the commands from the book. We still recommend the special
version of Debian described above, however, because it contains the
special VirtualBox extensions. Nonetheless, two other popular distributions
that have been tested with this book are: <emphasis>Fedora</emphasis> and
<emphasis>Ubuntu</emphasis>. Both are good and you can give them a try. At the
time of this writing, the latest version of Fedora is <emphasis>32</emphasis>
and the latest version of Ubuntu is <emphasis>groovy</emphasis>. To install
one of them, use one of the following commands instead.</para>

<screen>vagrant init fedora/32-cloud-base</screen>
<screen>vagrant init ubuntu/groovy64</screen>
</note>

</section>

<section><title>Step 4: Start the VM with Linux</title>

<para>When the installation is finished, start the virtual machine, so that
it runs in the background:</para>

<screen>vagrant up</screen>

<para>The above command will take a while, because that's the one that
actually downloads the distribution.</para>

</section>

<section><title>Step 5: Log in to Linux</title>

<para>To log in to Linux, type: </para>

<screen>vagrant ssh</screen>

<para>That's it! You now have a working Linux command line.</para>

</section>

<section><title>Step 6: Starting the VM after Host Reboot</title>

<para>If you reboot your host computer (that is your physical machine),
you need to start the VM again before you can log back in to it. Open the
command line and type the following:</para>

<screen>vagrant up</screen>

<para>Then log in as normal:</para>

<screen>vagrant ssh</screen>

</section>

<section><title>Bonus: Copying Files To and From the VM</title>

<para>If you've installed the recommended version of Debian, copying files
to and from the virtual machine is going to be super-easy as well. Files in
the directory on the host machine where the <filename>Vagrantfile</filename>
is located will be automatically visible in the <filename>/vagrant</filename>
directory in the virtual machine.</para>

<para>So if you want to share a file from the host to the VM, just put
it in the same directory as the <filename>Vagrantfile</filename>. And
if you want to share a file from the VM to the host, just put it in the
<filename>/vagrant</filename> directory.</para>

<para>Wondering how to copy files inside the virtual machine? <link
linkend="man_pages">Read the remaining chapters</link>, which will tell you
all you need to know about&nbsp;it&nbsp;:)</para>

</section>
