<abstract>

<para><citetitle>Linux Doesn't Have to Be Hard: A Beginner's Guide</citetitle>
will gently and humorously introduce you to the Linux operating system. It
comprehensively covers controlling the computer using the keyboard,
rather than the mouse, working with files, directories or text, as well
as automating common tasks. The book is intended for novice Linux systems
administrators or ordinary Linux users that want to learn more about their
operating system.</para>

<para>To make the most out of this book, you are advised to read it next to
a Linux machine, so that you can immediately practice what you learn.</para>

<para>The contents of the book include:
<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
<listitem>working with files and directories</listitem>
<listitem>combining commands using <command>pipes</command></listitem>
<listitem>transforming text using filtering commands</listitem>
<listitem>searching text for sophisticated patterns using powerful 
<command>regular expressions</command></listitem>
<listitem>saving time when typing commands by using helpful features of 
the <command>bash</command> command-line implementation</listitem>
<listitem>editing text using <command>vi</command>, a powerful editor 
for Linux gurus</listitem>
<listitem>automating repetitive tasks using <command>shell 
scripting</command></listitem>
<listitem>managing users on a Linux system</listitem>
<listitem>managing file security</listitem>
<listitem>accessing and searching Linux manuals</listitem>
<listitem>legal aspects of Linux, especially copyright 
licensing</listitem>
<listitem>a guide to Linux distributions</listitem>
<listitem>a brief history of Linux</listitem>
</itemizedlist></para>

<para>The book does not describe graphical end-user applications, such as web
browsers, video players or office suites, because they are not fundamental
features of the operating system.</para>

<para>This book belongs to the <citetitle>Userbie</citetitle> series of
guides, which are available gratis. They are community-developed and you
are encouraged to contribute. Click on the <emphasis>[feedback]</emphasis>
link, located at the end of every paragraph, to provide feedback to the
maintainers. If your suggested changes are incorporated into the guide,
your name will feature as a contributor to the guide.</para>

<para> This book has been originally written by Paul Cobbaut. Its
maintenance has since been taken over by Aleksander Korzynski and
the Userbie team. Only a part of the book has been updated by the
new maintainer so far. You can access the updated part at: <ulink
url="https://userbie.com/get-started-on-linux-in-32-minutes"
>userbie.com/get-started-on-linux-in-32-minutes</ulink>. To
receive notifications when subsequent parts of the book are released,
please subscribe to the <ulink url="https://userbie.com/newsletter">Userbie
Newsletter</ulink>.</para>

<para>This edition has been created by Aleksander Korzynski. Feel
free to contact him at ak@wants-no-spam.akorzy.com (remove
<emphasis>wants-no-spam.</emphasis>). His personal website is located at
<ulink url="http://www.akorzy.com">akorzy.com</ulink>.</para>

<para>The publisher of this edition is KZS Press, trading name of KZS
Commerce Ltd, 7 Kings Avenue, Manchester, Greater Manchester, M8 5AS,
United Kingdom.</para>

<para>Copyright &#169; 2007-2015, 2020 [COPYRIGHTS]</para>
<para>Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document
under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.3 published by
the Free Software Foundation; with no Front-Cover Texts, no Back-Cover Texts
and an Invariant Section entitled Preface; with Aleksander Korzynski as the
proxy for deciding if a later version of the license can be used. A copy of
the license is included in the section entitled <link linkend="license">GNU
Free Documentation License</link>.</para>

<para>Linux&#174; is the registered trademark of Linus Torvalds in the U.S. and
other countries. UNIX&#174; is a registered trademark of The Open Group.</para>

</abstract>
