<preface id="preface"><title>Preface</title>

<para>George is a friend of mine and a business owner and a few months ago he
asked me for advice. He employs a junior developer called Martin who complained
he was missing a senior developer on the team. Martin said that he didn't
know if he was coding properly or not. He wished there was someone to provide
feedback. George asked me if I could help. I said I could give a try for free
and if Martin liked it, we could talk about some sort of paid mentoring.</para>

<para>I read Martin’s code and it was good, but there was opportunity of
improvement. I spoke with Martin, but I didn't tell him all my ideas right
away. Instead, asked him questions that helped him come up with his own
ways to improve the code. A few days later George told me that Martin was
ecstatic! George hired me to mentor Martin and I realised I could do more
of this. I needed to write some course materials as well.</para>

<para>I’d had the idea for this book for months before that. Linux
documentation is scattered around the web, often out of date, incorrect or
incomplete. On the one hand, there’re some quality books, but they cost
money and readers cannot contribute to them. On the other hand, there’re
wikis, but they’re unreliable and tend to be a chaotic. I wanted to try
another model.</para>

<para>Here is how it works: the online version of this book has a
<emphasis>[feedback]</emphasis> link located at the end of every paragraph,
a simple way to provide feedback to the editors. If you provide feedback and
your suggested changes are incorporated into the book, your name will feature
as a contributor to the book. In this model we combine the collaborative
creativity of a wiki with the quality of a curated book!</para>

<para>To demonstrate the power of collaborative writing, I haven’t written
this book from scratch. Paul Cobbaut has written a great series of books
entitled <citetitle>Linux Training</citetitle>. Unfortunately, the books are
now out of date, as they last received modest updates in 2015. The <ulink
url="https://userbie.com">Userbie</ulink> series is an updated, restructured
and partially rewritten version of the original series, created by myself
and the Userbie team.</para>

<para>The book is completely Open Access &#8211; you don’t have
to pay to read it online. So how do we make money? You can <ulink
url="https://www.codementor.io/@akorzy">purchase live help over a video
link</ulink> or <ulink url="https://amzn.to/3gU0e8t">make a purchase from
Amazon using our affiliate link</ulink>, so that we earn a commission. Find
out more in the boxes below.</para>

<important><title>Stuck? Get Live Help</title>

<para>If you're stuck anywhere in the book, you can get live <ulink
url="https://www.codementor.io/@akorzy">help over a video link</ulink>,
using the CodeMentor platform. You can also get live long-term mentoring. You
won't get charged for the first 15 minutes.</para>

</important>

<important><title>Don't Want To Troubleshoot?</title>

<para>Don’t want to be bothered with troubleshooting Linux installation
issues? Purchase a <ulink url="https://amzn.to/3gU0e8t">pre-installed Linux
laptop</ulink>. If you click on that link and make any purchase on Amazon
afterwards, we’ll receive a commission, which will help with the development
and maintenance of the series.</para>

</important>

<para>In case you’re curious about the origin of the name Userbie, the Old
Norse suffix <emphasis>-bie</emphasis> means a village or settlement. Userbie
then means <emphasis>a village of users</emphasis>. The word Userbie also
rhymes with the word newbie.</para>

<para>I’ve put a lot of heart into preparing this book and I hope
you’re going to get a lot of value out of it. Please let me know about
your experiences with it. Has it helped you land a lucrative job? Have you
felt proud for what you’ve achieved with Linux? I’m looking forward to
hearing from you.</para>

<para>&#8211; Aleksander Korzyński:
ak&nbsp;AT&nbsp;wants-no-spam.akorzy.com</para>

</preface>
